我叫巴里·艾伦  是现今世上速度最快的人
My name is Barry Allen, and I am the fastest man alive.
我年幼时  看到自己的母亲
When I was a child, I saw my mother
-被令人难以置信的东西杀害  -快跑  巴里
- killed by something impossible. - Run, Barry. Run.
我父亲因为谋杀母亲进了监狱
My father went to prison for her murder.
但是一场事故让我也变得令人难以置信
Then an accident made me the impossible.
在外人看来  我只是个普通的鉴证专员
To the outside world, I'm an ordinary forensic scientist,
但我秘密地用自己的速度
but secretly, I use my speed
打击犯罪  寻找跟我一样的人
to fight crime and find others like me.
终有一天  我会找到杀害母亲的凶手
And one day, I'll find who killed my mother...
-妈妈  -让我父亲沉冤得雪
- Mom! - and get justice for my father.
我就是  闪电侠
I am the Flash.
《闪电侠》前情回顾
Previously, on the Flash-
没有迈泰鸡尾酒的蜜月不算蜜月
A honeymoon isn't a honeymoon without Mai Tais.
罗尼
Ronnie?
我不能让你有什么...
I can't let whatever happened..
罗尼
Ronnie!
我只希望能和他白头到老
I wanted him to be my husband.
从你知道爱为何物时
I have watched you be in love with Iris
我就一直知道你爱着爱瑞丝
since you were old enough to know what love is.
他杀了我妈妈
He killed my mom.
闪电侠
第二季第九集
一天前
就只剩两盒了
There's only two boxes left.
按照这个速度
You know, at this rate,
我们得到复活节才能装扮好
we'll be finished by Easter.
想都别想
Don't even.
现在我唯一想在这里看到的
Okay, the only red-suited dude
穿红色衣服的人
I want in this house right now
就只有克里斯·柯林格勒  知道吗
is Kris Kringle, you got it?
圣诞老人
这些饰品不会自己跑到圣诞树上吧
Uh, these ornaments are not gonna hang themselves.
-是啊  -埃丝特祖母的独家配方
- Mm-hmm. - Grandma Esther's recipe...
加了少许波本酒
light on the bourbon.
我就喜欢她对"少许"的定义
I always loved her definition of "Light."
圣诞传统真是一点都没变啊
And the Christmas tradition continues.
我是韦斯特警探  怎么了
Detective West. Yeah?
好吧
All right.
抱歉孩子们  地检想问我几个问题
Sorry, kids, the D.A. wants to ask me some questions.
我回来的时候可要给我留点蛋酒
Make sure there's some nog left for me when I get back.
可不保证哦
No promises.
你这是干什么
What's happening?
来嘛
Come on.
拜托  现在就要拆礼物吗
Oh, come on, we're doing this already?
还有好几天才是圣诞节呢
Christmas isn't for a few days.
我等不及了
I couldn't wait any longer.
等等  我先拆
Oh, wait, me first.
好吧
Okay.
我妈妈的结婚戒指
My mother's wedding band?
仿制的
A replica, yeah.
你把真的丢了时那么伤心
You were devastated when you lost the real one.
我们五年级野游...
Our fifth-grade field trip...
去动物园的时候
to the zoo.
你哭了好几周
You cried for weeks.
我给你戴上
Here.
你还记得
You remembered.
当然
Yeah.
历历在目
Steel trap.
我都不知道说什么好了
I don't know what to say.
相比之下我的礼物好逊...
My gift so sucks in comparison...
-顺便告诉你  -怎么会
- by the way. - No.
这应该是市面上最好的了
It's supposed to be the best one on the market.
你觉得你也该换台新的了
I thought you could maybe use a new one.
太逊了  我知道
It's lame, I know.
不不  这礼物很棒啊  我很喜欢
No, no, this is great. I love it.
-真的吗  -当然是真的
- Yeah? - Yeah, of course.
亲爱的你来了
Hey, babe.
你好巴里  戒指不错啊
Hey, Barry. Nice ring.
很漂亮对吧
It's beautiful, isn't it?
这是我妈妈戒指的复制品
It's an exact replica of my mom's.
巴里送给我的
Barry got it for me.
想的真周到啊  巴仔
Very thoughtful, Bar.
-话说要装饰圣诞树吗  -当然
- So are we tree trimming? - Yeah.
来吧
Come on.
圣诞快乐
Merry Christmas.
小小礼物略表谢意...
Just a small token of my gratitude...
谢谢你们这一年来为我做的一切
for everything you guys have done for me this year.
当我说你是上天赐予我们的礼物时  巴里
I think I speak on behalf of my colleagues
我是代表大家一起说的
when I say you've been a gift for us, Barry.
那是什么
What's that?
这是爱瑞丝送的礼物
This is compliments of Iris,
埃丝特祖母最出名的蛋奶酒
Grandma Esther's famous eggnog.
有蛋奶酒的圣诞才是圣诞
That's what I'm talking about.
我迟会再喝吧
Maybe later for me.
我可不想醉酒驾驶
Wouldn't want to drink and drive.
我是不是说错话了
Did I say something wrong?
-没有啊  -不是你的问题
- No. - No, man.
圣诞节曾经是他最喜欢的节日
He, this used to be his favorite time of year,
但后来在圣诞节前夕出了事  所以
but the accident happened before Christmas, so,
他没什么心情过节
kind of ruined the holidays.
我要去给他买个礼物
I'm gonna go get him a present.
也许能让他开心起来
Maybe that'll cheer him up.
谢谢你的礼物
Thank you very much.
西斯科  你圣诞节有什么打算吗
So what are you doing for Christmas, Cisco?
我问你衬衣的尺码
The fact that I asked you for your shirt size
可不代表我圣诞节
should in no way indicate
要给你买的礼物是与衬衣相关的
that I am getting you something shirt-related for Christmas.
巴里今天看起来怪怪的
Barry seemed a little odd today.
他应该不是因为我来了才这样吧
I'm pretty sure he wasn't psyched I came by.
你有没有想过
You ever think
他有可能喜欢你
he maybe might like you?
什么  别搞笑了
What? No.
但是普通朋友是不会送婚戒的啊
Friends don't give friends wedding bands.
他又不是在跟我求婚  傻瓜
He was, he wasn't proposing to me, silly.
我们只是好朋友而已
He and I are just best friends.
那他应该不介意我这么做
Well, then he won't be bothered by this.
我知道现在有点早  可我等不及了
A bit early, but I couldn't wait.
我们在一起已经一年了
I figured we've been together a year now.
而你几乎每晚都留下来过夜
You pretty much stay there most nights anyway.
我爱你
I love you.
那我就当你答应我了
That's a yes, I take it?
不选那个的话就是斯蒂芬·霍金新出的自传
It was that or Stephen Hawking's new autobiography,
而我们都知道他对霍金的看法
and we both know how he feels about Hawking.
我等下再跟你聊  再见  西斯科
Okay, I'll talk to you later. Bye, Cisco.
超光速研究中心
圣诞快乐  博士
Merry Christmas, doc.
-谢谢你  吉米  -也谢谢你
- Thank you, Jimmy. - And to you.
博士  我知道这是个大秘密
Hey, doc, I know it's a big secret,
不过你能给点提示吗
but can you give me a hint?
你在这里研究的到底是什么
What exactly are you working on in there?
我研究的是未来
The future.
博士  快进去
Doctor, get inside!
封锁整栋楼
Lock down the facility!
你怎么看
What are you thinking?
从血液的喷溅痕迹和尸体的移动轨迹来看
The blood splatter patterns and trajectory of the remains,
只有高速的冲撞能造成这种惨剧
only a high-speed collision could have done this.
但要在这里对一个人造成这么大的伤害
But to cause this type of damage to a human in this space?
撞到他们的东西速度得非常快
Whatever hit them would have to have been moving fast.
听听这个
Get this.
目击者说他看见了一抹疾影
The witness says all he saw was a blur.
听起来耳熟吗
Sound familiar?
你看见了一抹疾影
You saw a blur?
什么样的影子
W-what was it?
不管那是什么  它在找某些东西
Whatever it was, it was looking for something.
那它长什么样
Well, what did it look like?
感觉像是一个穿黄衣服的人
Like a-a man in some kind of yellow suit.
好的
OK.
-巴里  -我得去看下我的文件
- Barry, listen-- - I have to check my files.
乔  你听见他说的了
Joe, you heard him, all right?
杀害我母亲的人又出现了
The man that killed my mom, he's back.
我知道
I know.
他已经在城里好几周了
He's been in town for a few weeks now.
他来我家找过我
He paid a visit to me at the house.
他把你母亲案子里的所有证据都带走了
He took all the evidence from your mom's case.
文件都没了
The files are gone.
你为什么不早点告诉我
Why wouldn't you tell me this sooner?
-我不能说  -为什么
- I couldn't. - Why?
因为他威胁要杀了爱瑞丝
Because he threatened to kill Iris.
目击者声称看见一抹黄色疾影
The witness described seeing a yellow blur
跟杀掉巴里妈妈的人一样
just like the one that killed Barry's mother.
那我们得开始行动  阻止这个超速变态
Then we need to get cracking and stop this speed psycho.
我不是想给他起名来着
That--I wasn't trying to give him a name.
水星实验室的犯罪现场
The crime scene at Mercury Labs
位于有着高强度防护罩的那一层
was on a floor with highly secured vaults,
目击者说他像是在找什么东西
and the witness said he was looking for something.
不管是什么  他不惜一切都想得到它
Whatever it was, he wanted it badly enough to kill for it.
博士  你了解水星实验室吗
Doctor, what do you know about this Mercury Labs?
在尖端科研实验室的小挫败之前
Mercury was one of S.T.A.R. Labs'
水星实验室是我们的主要竞争对手
major competitors until our little setback,
后来聪明却自我的物理学家
and then it catapulted to the forefront
克里斯蒂娜·麦吉博士
led by Dr. Christina Mcgee,
让它一举成名
brilliant but egocentric physicist.
水星实验室  未来技术的肥沃新月地带
这里说麦吉博士
It says here Dr. Mcgee
筹集了五亿美金民间资金来发展
has secured half a billion dollars in private funding to develop,
我引用一下  "未来技术模型"
and I quote, "Prototypes for the technology of the future."
我也认为是
Well, I'll be.
蒂娜在研究超光子
Tina's messing with tachyons,
超光速粒子
superluminal particles.
当然
Of course.
可以干嘛  拿那些叫...
So what could someone do with one of those...
-超光子  -谢谢
- Tachyons. - Thank you.
我不知道  可以变得无敌
Well, I don't know. Become invincible?
如果你能设计一个足够稳定的模型
If you could devise a matrix stable enough
来利用它们的能量
to harness their power,
你能比光速还快
you could travel faster than light.
他肯定会再次尝试去抢它们的
He's gonna try to get them again,
所以我们得拿水星实验室的东西作为诱饵
so we need to get what Mercury has and use it as a lure.
没错
Exactly right.
西斯科  凯特琳  我们开始设置陷阱
Cisco, Caitlin, let's start engineering a trap.
-没问题  -好的
- You got it. - Of course.
谢谢
Thanks.
爱瑞丝
Iris.
凯特琳  你怎么来了
Caitlin. What are you doing here?
这一天过得可糟心了
Oh, it's been a long day.
现在才到中午而已
It's only noon.
我昨晚没怎么睡
I didn't sleep much last night.
我也是
Yeah, me either.
我一直在追你的博客
Um, so I was catching up on your blog,
有个故事吸引了我
and this story caught my eye--
关于有个人的头和手会燃烧成火焰的
about a man whose head and hands burst into flames?
-火人吗  -是的
- The burning man? - Yeah.
我有一阵子没更新那篇了
I haven't really updated that story in a while,
但我可以发些报道给你
but there are some reports that I could send you.
那真是太好了  谢谢
That'd be great. Thank you.
我能问你点事吗
Can I ask you something,
女孩之间的
girl-to-girl?
当然可以
Sure.
巴里最近对我怪怪的
Barry's been acting different around me lately,
好像对我隐藏了什么秘密
like he's keeping some sort of secret from me.
你知道什么我应该知道的事情吗
Is there anything that you know about that I should know about?
我想不到有什么
Not that I can think of.
但是  如果你觉得巴里对你隐瞒了什么
However, if you feel like Barry's keeping something from you,
你应该自己去问他
you should probably just ask him yourself.
是的
Yeah.
-谢谢你  -不客气
- Thanks. - Of course.
好了  我得去拿咖啡了
Yeah, Okay. Gonna get some caffeine.
我是巴里·艾伦  谢谢你过来
Barry Allen. Thank you for coming in.
我是蒂娜·麦吉博士
Dr. Tina Mcgee.
我猜是关于昨夜闯入的事情
I assume this is about last night's break-in?
是也不是
Well, yes and no.
那是你实验室里经常发生的事
That's usually how things are with you,
不是吗  哈里森
aren't they, Harrison?
我们认为不管闯入的人是谁
We believe that whoever broke in
都是想拿你的模型
was after one of your prototypes.
你得缩小点范围
You'll have to narrow that down.
我们有几百个在研发的模型
We have literally hundreds of projects in development.
有超光速粒子的那个
One containing tachyonic particles.
我们在超光速粒子研究上成绩喜人  没错
We've had encouraging success with tachyons, yes,
但是在模型和现实运用之间
but there's still a significant gap between our prototype
还存在巨大差距
and any real-life application.
我们希望你能把你的模型
we were hoping you would lend us
借给我们作为诱饵
your prototype to use as a lure.
我们
"Us"?
你现在在协助警方了吗  哈里森
You're assisting the police now, Harrison?
我给这个特殊案件做顾问
I'm consulting on this particular case.
蒂娜  这个人一旦被逮捕
Listen, Tina, once this man is apprehended,
你的模型会马上还给你的
your prototype will be promptly returned.
你知道没有人比我更希望
You know nobody wants to ensure
确保未来技术的安全性
the future's technology more than me.
我很感谢中城警署为我考虑  艾伦先生
I appreciate the CCPD's concerns, Mr. Allen,
但是水星实验室完全有能力保护其自身的财产
but Mercury is quite capable of protecting its own assets.
祝你们追捕行动顺利
Good luck with your manhunt.
凯特琳  来看这个
Hey, Caitlin, check this out.
我认为我们可以造一个电子屏障
I think we can fashion an electronic barrier, right?
设置大量的超级电容器
We set up a ton of super capacitors.
使拐点变得平滑
We smooth out the inflection points,
瞧
and voila--
一个可以困住反闪的强大力场就建成了
a kick-ass force field to trap the Opposite Flash.
这是我临时给他起的名字
That was me testing out a name.
你认为怎么样
What do you think?
你怎么了
Are you okay?
罗尼还活着
Ronnie's alive.
我看到他了  西斯科
I saw him, Cisco.
我觉得他好像在跟踪我
I think he was following me.
凯特琳
Caitlin...
罗尼死了
Ronnie died.
加速器达到临界状态时  他被蒸发了
He was vaporized in the accelerator when it went critical.
罗尼还活着
Ronnie's alive,
他在外面孤独且恐惧地活着
and he's out there alone and scared,
我需要你帮我找到他
and I need your help to find him.
医生被指控杀妻
亨利·艾伦  凶杀罪
你的伤已经在痊愈了
Your bruise is already healing.
但还是很疼
It still hurts, though.
很快就不会再疼了  宝贝
Not for much longer, honey.
过来
Here, come on.
我不会关灯的
I'll keep the light on for you.
你有过怕黑吗
Were you ever afraid of the dark?
如果我现在把灯关掉
If I turn this light off now,
你会害怕吗
would you be scared?
不会
No.
那是因为我现在陪着你
That's because I'm here with you.
你并不是怕黑  巴里
See, you're not afraid of the dark, Barry.
你只是害怕独自待在黑暗中
You're afraid of being alone in the dark,
当你意识到这点时你就不再害怕了
and that goes away when you realize something.
你永远都不会独自一人的
You're never really alone.
该睡觉了
It's time for bed.
我渴了
I'm thirsty.
才没有  你在拖时间
Oh, no, you're stalling.
不过我掩护你  伙计
But I got you covered, buddy.
晚安  小拳王
Good night, slugger.
做个好梦  我的宝贝
Sweet dreams, my beautiful boy.
你可以把灯关掉
You can turn off the light.
本地医生杀妻  儿子幸存
妈妈  妈妈
Mom! Mom!
诺拉
Nora!
巴里
Barry.
我叫了你好多次...
I called your name, like...
你妈妈的案子
Your mom's case.
我以前天天都会研究这个案板
I used to study this board every day.
最近  我几乎连看
Lately, I haven't looked at it
都没怎么看过
as much as I should have.
我不知道你以前会这样做
I didn't know you did that.
我想我还有一些事  是你不知道的
I guess there's still some stuff about me you don't know.
艾迪让我搬过去和他一起住
Eddie asked me to move in with him.
我同意了
I said yes.
你俩进展可真快
You guys are moving pretty fast, huh?
我们的确才交往了一年
Well, I mean, it's been a year.
艾迪认为你可能会觉得奇怪
Eddie thought you might feel weird about it.
什么  我不会
Wha--I don't--
他为什么这样说
Why would he say that?
他认为你...
He thinks that you...
对我有男女之间的爱意
like me romantically.
说实话  有这想法
I mean, honestly, it sounds even silly
都挺傻的
suggesting it.
艾迪猜错了
I mean, Eddie's wrong.
如果我以前有奇怪的表现
I--and if I've seemed weird before,
那只是
it's just
因为今年过得真的很快
that this year has gone by really fast,
也许我没意识到
and I guess I didn't realize
你们在一起有多久了
how far along in your relationship you guys were.
我也是这么和他说的
That's what I told him.
我想我该走了
Well, I guess i should get going.
拜
Bye.
是你
It was you.
那晚出现在我家的就是你
You were the one in my house that night.
是你杀了我妈妈
You killed my mother!
为什么
Why?
如果你想知道原因
If you want to know that,
先追上我再说
you're gonna have to catch me.
不够快  闪电侠
Not fast enough, Flash.
-你是谁  -你知道我是谁  巴里
- Who are you? - You know who I am, Barry.
我不知道你是谁
I don't know who you are.
你知道的  巴里
But you do, Barry.
你和我不止一次像今天这样对峙了
We've been at this a long time, you and I,
可我总是领先你一步
but I'm always one step ahead.
你注定要输给我  闪电侠
It is your destiny to lose to me, Flash,
正如你妈妈注定要在那天晚上
just as it was your mother's destiny
死去一样
to die that night.
他好像认识我  好像我们以前做过同样的事
He acted like he knew me, like we'd done this before.
他在激怒你  巴仔
He was antagonizing you, Bar.
我快接近他了  可是他却闪开了
I would get close, and he'd just pull away.
他似乎在故意耍我
I mean, this was just some sick game to him.
我们会助你追上他的
You'll catch him. We'll help.
不  你们不明白
No, you don't get it, all right?
他的速度远远超过我
His speed, it is-- it's beyond me.
我不是现今世上速度最快的人  他才是
I'm not the fastest man alive. He is.
我连追都追不上他  要怎么才能抓住他
So how do we catch somebody that even I can't keep up with?
分子力场的美妙之处  艾伦先生
The beautiful thing about force fields, Mr. Allen,
在于它们不受速度的影响
is they're impervious to speed.
我们的陷阱就快制作完成了
Now, we're almost finished fabricating the trap,
现在只需要韦斯特警探把诱饵弄到手
and all that remains is for Detective West to procure the bait.
我这就去办
I'm on it.
巴里  你不如留在这吧
Barry, why don't you stay here?
不  乔  今天不是我该留下的时候
No, Joe, today is not the day to tell me to stay behind.
如果汉克森法官会签署这份文件
If Judge Hankerson was gonna sign this,
中城巡回法院  密封  申请驳回
他早就签了
he would have done so already.
我相信你不希望这次调查
Look, I'm sure you don't want this investigation
引起外界更多的关注吧  博士
to get any more public than it's already been, do you, doctor?
哈里森·威尔斯已经白纸黑字写得很清楚了
This has Harrison Wells written all over it in big black letters.
我是不会把我的超光速粒子原型交给你们的
I am not giving you my tachyon prototype.
你那里的设施让我大饱眼福  博士
It was quite the tour of your facility, doctor.
你可以像耍猴一样对待那些愚蠢的警察
You were fine to let us dumb cops walk around,
可我主修的是物理和化学
but I majored in physics and chemistry,
我看到了很多
and I saw a whole lot of stuff
会让《科学陈列柜杂志》感兴趣的东西
that Science Show Case Magazine would love to hear about.
我是该直接给他们的主编打电话呢
So should I call their editors directly
还是在他们的网站上留言呢
or just leave a few posts on their website?
一小时之内我会把超光速粒子装置交给你们
You'll have the tachyon device within the hour.
我知道哈里森为何如此尊重你了  艾伦先生
I see why Harrison holds you in such esteem, Mr. Allen.
因为你们非常相像
You're very much alike.
干得好
Nicely done.
-乔  有空吗  -现在不行  艾迪
- Hey, Joe, you got a second? - Not now, Eddie.
我看了目击者的证词  闪电侠当时在现场
I read the witness statement. The Flash was there.
我知道你在计划某事
I know you got something in the works.
是的  但是你不会想参与其中的
Yeah, but you don't want any part of this.
我申请逮捕他的特别行动小组已经批下来了
I've got a task force approved to capture him,
我要求加入
and I want in.
我不是在征求你的同意  乔
I'm not asking permission, Joe.
你说什么
Excuse me?
如果我的特别行动小组不能参与此事
If my task force isn't a part of this,
我会去找辛格队长
I'll go to Captain Singh.
我会和他说有事发生  而你却不肯透露
I'll tell him something's going on, and you're not talking-
抱歉
I'm sorry.
换做你是我  你也会这么做
You'd do the same thing if you were me.
好吧
Fine.
我们跟着电离粒子
We follow the ionized particles,
那应该能帮我们找到他
and that should lead us right to him.
浓缩微粒物质在上升
The CPMs are increasing.
我们应该告诉威尔斯博士和巴里的
We should have told Dr. Wells and Barry.
不行  等到我们确认了再说
No, not until we're sure it's him.
罗尼不再是你记得的样子了
Look, Ronnie is not like you remembered him.
那是什么意思
What does that mean?
你看到他的时候别被吓到  好吗
Just don't freak out when you see him, okay?
我真希望这是因为没电了
Oh, I really wish that was because the batteries were dead.
罗尼
Ronnie?
罗尼  是我  凯特
Ronnie, it's me, Cait.
我带了西斯科来
Look, I brought Cisco with me.
我们是来帮你的
We're here to help you.
你经历了一场意外  记得吗
You were in an accident. Do you remember?
我不是罗尼
I'm not Ronnie.
你是  你是罗尼·雷蒙德
Yes, you are. You're Ronnie Raymond.
我不是罗尼  我跟你说了
I'm not Ronnie. I told you that.
现在离我远点
Now get away from me.
我们需要把你带回尖端科研实验室
Look, we just need to take you back to S.T.A.R. Labs.
我们会帮你记起自己是谁的
We'll help you remember who you are.
烈焰风暴
Firestorm.
超光速粒子设备已经就位
The tachyon device is in place.
你觉得会有用吗
You think it'll work?
会有用的
It'll work.
那我们怎么告诉他原型在我们这
So how do we advertise to him that the prototype's here?
我们会搞定的
We'll take care of that.
怎么了
What's the problem?
巴里
Look, Barry...
我和威尔斯博士谈过了
Me and Dr. Wells have spoken, and...
我们觉得你最好不要参与这事
we think it would be best if you weren't here for this.
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
你跟这案子的关系太紧密了
You're too close to this.
也许是你跟这个案子的关系不够紧密
Or maybe you're not close enough.
如果不是你几周前太害怕
If you hadn't been too scared
没有提醒我他在这
and warned me that he was here weeks ago,
我本可以有所准备
I could have been prepared for this.
我想我们都能理解乔对爱瑞丝的关心  巴里
I think we can all appreciate Joe's concern for Iris, Barry.
所以我一定要在这里
That's why I have to be here!
我最有可能抓到这个人
I'm the best chance at catching this guy!
现在不行  你这种状态更不行
Not right now, not in this state.
这个人把我妈妈捅死了
This man stabbed my mother through the heart
而我爸爸却为此进了监狱
and sent my father to prison for it.
这是我的战争
This is my fight.
今天不行  孩子
Not today, son.
凯特琳
Caitlin...
别担心
don't worry.
既然我们知道罗尼还活着  就会再次找到他
Now that we know he's out there, we will find Ronnie again.
找他干什么
Why?
那我们就可以把他
So we can throw him in there
跟其他的变态超能力者们关起来吗
with all the other Meta-human psychos?
我常常在脑海中玩这个游戏
I used to play this game in my head.
若能再多跟他待一分钟  我愿意放弃什么
What would I give up for just one more minute with him?
我的房子  我的事业
My house, my career...
我的余生
the rest of my life?
今天我终于有了这么一分钟
Today I finally got that minute.
我多希望我没有
And I wish I hadn't.
看到他那样  他变成的样子
Seeing him like that, what he's become...
天呐
Dear God...
我希望他那天就死了
I wish he had just died that day.
圣诞快乐  小拳手
Merry Christmas, slugger.
圣诞快乐
Merry Christmas.
你没事吧  巴里
You all right, Barry?
我搞砸了  爸爸
I screwed up, dad.
经过这么多年的搜寻
After years of searching...
我终于找到他了
I finally found him.
我找到杀死妈妈的凶手
I found the man who killed mom...
黄衣人  闪电中的人
The man in yellow, the one in the lightning.
他就在某处  我跟他交手了
He's out there, and I had him.
他跑了
He got away.
我... 只差那么一点
I-I was so close.
我发誓我会把你救出来
I promised you that I would get you out of here.
你在这的每一天都是因为他
Every day you spend in here has been because of him...
直到今天
Until today.
现在你出不来是因为我  我很抱歉
Now you're in here because of me, and I'm so sorry.
我
I...
巴里
Barry.
巴里  这不是你的错
Barry, this is not your fault.
看着我
Look at me.
我知道你都放弃了什么
I know what you've given up.
这14年来你做的每一个决定
Every decision you've made in the past 14 years
都是因为我和你妈妈
has been because of me and your mom--
你所学的东西
what you studied,
成为犯罪现场鉴证员  甚至还有爱瑞丝
why you became a CSI, even with Iris.
-爱瑞丝  -你是我儿子
- Iris? - You're my son.
你以为我不知道你有多爱她吗
You don't think I know how you love her?
但你从未追求过她
But you never pursued her
因为你太在意我和你妈妈的事
because you were too consumed with what happened to me
以至于失去了自己的生活
and your mom to let yourself have a life.
放手吧  巴里
Well, let it go now, Barry.
听我的
Hear me now.
那个黄衣人
The man in the yellow suit...
已经从我们家夺走了太多
has taken enough from us already.
不要让他继续得逞了
Don't let him take any more.
来得正好
Just in time.
我就快弄好了
I am almost done.
装扮圣诞树有什么奖励吗
Are there awards for tree trimming?
因为这装扮可以拿去评奖了
Because this is award-worthy.
你没事吧  巴仔
Are you okay, Bar?
我爱你  爱瑞丝
I love you, Iris.
我也爱你
Oh, I love you too.
我们还是小孩的时候  在我知道
When we were kids, I loved you
什么是爱以前  我就爱上你了
before I even knew what the word "love" meant.
然后我妈妈去世了
And then my mom died,
我不得不住在我暗恋的女孩家里
and I had to go live with the girl that I had a crush on.
我
Look, I--
有那么多次
there were so many times
我都想告诉你
that I wanted to tell you--
高三舞会  我去上大学时
junior prom, when I went away to college,
从大学回来时
when I came back from college,
我们熬夜聊天的晚上  那些生日聚会上
nights that we stayed up talking, all the birthdays,
那么多的圣诞节里  但我从未说出来
all the Christmases, but I-I never did.
我只是闷在心里
I just -- I kept it in.
在我失去了爸妈之后
After I lost my mom and my dad,
我害怕  如果你不喜欢我
I was afraid that if you didn't feel the same way,
我会连你也失去
I would lose you, too.
说来真可笑
That's the irony.
我那么怕失去你  却因此而失去了你
I was so scared of losing you that I did.
我知道  我有太多机会可以告诉你
I know I've had our whole lives to tell you this,
我知道你现在和艾迪在一起
and you're with Eddie now, and I know that,
我也知道时机选的太糟
and I know my timing couldn't be any worse,
但是我
but I just--
没法再瞒下去了
I couldn't lie to you any more.
对不起
I'm sorry.
我走吧
Okay.
发出下一波脉冲
Sending out another pulse.
你确定这个陷阱有用吗
Are you certain this trap will work?
我已经向开放卫星发送了三波脉冲
I've sent up at least three charges into open satellite.
如果真有人在找超光速粒子
If anyone's looking tachyonic particles,
他们会知道在我们手里
they'll know we got them.
看看我们抓到了什么
Let's see what we caught.
西斯科  开灯
Cisco? Lights.
好的  威尔斯博士
Sure thing, Dr. Wells.
斯旺警探  跟他宣读一下他的权利吧
Detective Thawne, would you like to read him his rights?
乔  你干什么
Joe, what are you doing?
寻求解答
Getting some answers.
14年前  你谋杀了诺拉·艾伦
14 years ago, you murdered Nora Allen.
为什么
I want to know why.
Why?
威尔斯博士  我们终于见面了
Dr. Wells, we meet at last.
你要超光速粒子干什么
What do you want with the tachyonic particles?
你理解不了我的目标
My goals are beyond your understanding.
是吗  我还算是个比较聪明的人
Oh, I don't know, I'm a pretty smart guy.
我知道你速度格外的快
I knew you were exceptionally fast,
所以我们制造的陷阱必须是肉眼不可见的
so any trap we manufactured would have to be invisible.
我知道你的细胞
I knew your cells
可以以很快的速度进行修复
could repair themselves at extraordinary speeds,
所以你可以抵抗住
so you could withstand
这东西对你身体所造成的伤害
the damage this is doing to your body right now.
超级电容器
The super capacitors--
牢笼正在波动
The containment field is fluctuating.
他们必须马上离开那里
They need to get out of there now.
我知道这些  是因为你的能力
The reason I know all this is because your powers
与闪电侠的完全一样
are almost exactly like those of the Flash.
我可与闪电侠不同
Oh, I'm not like the Flash at all.
可以说我们是相反的
Some would say I'm the reverse.
威尔斯博士  快撤
Dr. Wells, evacuate!
快离开那里
Get out of there now!
威尔斯博士
Dr. Wells!
西斯科  关闭护障
Cisco, turn off the barrier!
如果我关掉  那东西就会跑出来
If I turn it off, that thing's gonna get out.
西斯科  他会杀了威尔斯的
Cisco, he's gonna kill Wells!
找到他
Find him!
求助  凯特琳·斯诺
不许动  否则我们就开枪了
Don't move, or we will shoot.
我警告过你不要追捕我
I warned you not to hunt me.
巴里
Barry!
我们的赛跑还没结束呢
Our race is not yet done.
下回见  闪电侠
See you soon, Flash.
不要再找我了
Don't look for me again.
为什么它
Why did it...
不杀了我
not kill me?
我不知道  艾迪
I don't know, Eddie.
但是有东西你知道却没告诉我
But you know more than you've been telling me.
他们叫做超能力者
They're called meta-humans.
超能力者
"Meta-humans"?
有着超级能力的人
People with very powerful abilities.
你和我是警队里
You and me are the only guys
唯一知道事情真相的人
on the force that know what's really going on.
并且我们要保持现状
And we need to keep it that way...
这样其他人才不会受伤
So nobody else gets hurt.
你能做到吗
Can you do that?
那闪电侠呢
And the Flash?
你知道他是谁吗
Do you know who he is?
是的  我知道
Yeah, I do.
他是今晚救了我们俩的人
He's the guy that saved both of our lives tonight.
我一直在研究数据
I've been going over the data,
但我还是不知道为什么囚禁系统失败了
and I still don't know why the containment system failed.
我一定是漏了什么
I must have missed something.
对不起
I'm sorry.
那不是你的错  西斯科
It's not your fault, Cisco.
但如果你俩觉得有必要道歉
But if you both feel the need to apologize for something,
不如从没有告诉我罗尼还活着开始
you might start with the not telling me that Ronnie is still alive.
是我叫西斯科不要说的
I asked Cisco not to say anything.
当我看到罗尼的变化
Once I saw what Ronnie had become,
我需要
I needed...
我需要时间来确定是否能拯救他
I needed time to see if I could make him whole again.
我很抱歉  我知道你很生气
I'm sorry. I know you're mad.
没有
No.
如果我是你
I don't know what I would have done differently
可能也会做同样的事
in your situation.
我知道我向你做了很多保证
I know I have made you a lot of promises.
我知道我没能一一实现
I know I've not been able to keep them all.
但以性命起誓  我向你保证
But on my life, I promise you this...
我们会把罗尼带回家的
we will bring Ronnie home.
巴仔
Hey, Bar.
你知道我妈妈环游过世界两次吗
You know my mom traveled around the world twice?
她在西班牙呆过一学期
She spent a semester abroad in Spain,
她爱死那里了 以至于毕业后
and she loved it so much that after she graduated,
她就去了欧洲
she went to Europe.
在游览了几十座城市后才停下
Didn't stop till she'd been to a few dozen other cities.
她总想回去  但一直没有机会
She always wanted to go back, but she never got a chance.
你上大学的时候我曾提议送你出国
I offered to send you abroad when you were in college.
我知道  我记得  我...
Yeah, I know. I remember. I...
我无法放下担子
I couldn't take off.
我是说  说真的
I mean, the truth is
我被困在这里了...
I'm stuck here...
被困在中城了
in Central City.
十四年来  我都被恐惧困在那个客厅里
Fear has kept me in that living room for 14 years.
乔  我因为你害怕
Joe, I-I was mad at you
而生你的气
for being scared.
但事实上
But I mean, the truth is
真正害怕的人是我
I was the one that was scared.
我一生
I've been afraid of the man in yellow
都在害怕那个黄衣人
for my whole life.
所以我迷失了
That's why I lost.
你刚搬来跟我们住的时候
When you first moved in with us,
我以为我会承受不住
I thought it was gonna be too much.
我已经是个单亲爸爸  经济拮据
I'm already a single dad. Finances were tough.
而你是个刚失去母亲的小男孩
And you were a little boy who just lost his mother.
但其实我错了
But, man, was I wrong.
不到两周  你就把家里的气氛变得活跃
Within two weeks, you had changed the whole dynamic of the house.
很快  整个家都充满了...
Suddenly, the house was filled with this...
光亮...
light..
这种活力
this energy.
你把一切都点亮了
I mean, you brightened up everything.
你经历的黑暗比任何人毕生经历的都多
You'd seen more darkness than any man will in a lifetime,
可你却没让它侵蚀你的灵魂
and you never let it dim your soul.
我曾经以为  我因为收养你
So there I was, thinking that I'm changing your life
而改变了你的人生  而...
by taking you in, but...
事实上...
the truth is...
是你改变了我的人生
you changed mine.
所以你要继续发光  巴仔
So don't lose that light now, Bar,
世界可能需要闪电侠  但...
the world may need the Flash, but...
我需要我的巴里·艾伦
I need my Barry Allen.
我们回家吧
Let's go home.
好
Yeah.
你们怎么来了
Hey. What are you guys doing here?
我邀请他们来的
I invited them.
威尔斯博士去哪里了
Where's Dr. Wells?
他不喜欢出席社交聚会
Uh, he wasn't feeling up to a social gathering,
不过他很感激你邀请他
but he appreciated the invitation.
-来点蛋奶酒吗  -好
- Eggnog? - Yes.
圣诞快乐  巴里
Merry Christmas, Barry.
你也是  艾迪
You too, Eddie.
我...
Hey, I, um...
我只是想说...
Well, I just wanted to say, um...
我听说你们搬到一起住了
I heard you're moving in together,
我真为你们感到高兴
and I'm really happy for you.
谢谢
Thanks.
圣诞快乐
Merry Christmas.
相对今天的经历
Day like today,
埃丝特祖母的蛋奶酒好像波本放少了
Grandma Esther's eggnog seems a little light on the bourbon.
乔
Hey, Joe.
我今晚看见了奇怪的东西
I saw something weird tonight.
西斯科  我也看见了
Yeah, Cisco, I saw it too.
不  我是说
No, I mean,
当闪电侠和黄衣人
when the Flash and The Man in Yellow
全力相撞在一起时
were going full-on bumper cars on each other,
我看见电流从他们身上出来了
I was watching the electricity coming off of them--
黄色和红色的电流
yellow and red electricity.
巴里说他小时候
When Barry was a kid,
他母亲过世的那晚
he said he saw red and yellow lightning in his house
他家里出现了红色和黄色闪电
the night his mother died.
所以是两个人
There were two of them.
可能是黄衣人杀了巴里的母亲
The man in yellow may have killed Barry's mother,
但...
but...
那晚还有别的高速者
There was another speedster there that night.
爸爸  到时间了
Dad, it's time.
好  让我们瞧瞧
Okay, let's see.
圣诞快乐
Merry Christmas.